TV를 볼 때에는 밝은 방에서 적당히 떨어져서 보도록 해!
While you're watching the television...
Selama menonton acara ini
...be sure to keep your distance and watch in a well-lit room!
pastikan berada di jarak yang cukup dan di ruangan yang terang!
Plan
Webdiver Production Committee
Original Plan
Ishikawa Hiroto
yume ni yobare te… nami ni makare te…
Dennou Boukenki
Series Composition
Chief Director
Sekijima Mayori
Okajima Kunitoshi
fukai KAOSU no mori wo nuketara
Character Design
Takahashi Naruyo
kimi no kokoro de nanika ga kawaru
gin'iro no yoake ga ima
nagai nemuri wo uchikudaku you ni
Concept Design
Color Scheme
Moriki Yasuhiro
Kawami Takuya
kimi no inochi ni PARUSU wo okuru
hitasura ni ikiru tame ni
Production Designer
Director of Audiography
Composite Director
Iwase Eiji
Tanaka Hideyuki
Nagaushi Yutaka
kimi no hitomi no naka umareta bakarino
Music
Music Producer
Music Collaboration
Hayashi Yuzo
Kumada Kazuo
Television Tokyo Music
yume no kakera wo tsuyosa ni kaete yuke
Opening Theme
Lyrics
Composer/Arrangement
Oikawa Neko
Hirama Akihiko
Song
Columbia Japan
jidai ni tobikomu yuuki no DIVER
Production Collaboration
Animation Production
Animation Producer
AEON (We've)
Kachihide Yuki
Nomura Hiroshi
ima no kurushimi ya namida wo
oyogiki retanara mirai de kitto
Producer
Iwata Makiko (TV Tokyo)
Yamazaki Tatsuji
kimi mo HIRO ni nareru sa
afureru chikara douka shinjite
Director
Negishi Hiroshi
kagayaku tame ni tabitate SOLDIER
Production
나는 계속 찾아왔다.
I've been searching until now.
Selama ini, aku masih mencari-cari.
강한 의지를 가진 자를.
The one with a strong will.
Orang dengan tekad yang kuat.
나와 함께 싸울 자격이 있는
The one who's suitable to fight with me
Orang yang memiliki jiwa kesatria
전사의 혼을 가진 자여.
and bears a warrior's soul.
dan sepadan denganku.
전사의 혼...
A warrior's soul...
Jiwa kesatria...
너에게도 들릴 테다.
You must have heard it by now.
Pasti kau bisa mendengarnya juga.
더욱 강한 적과의 전투를 원하는 목소리가.
A voice that desires a fight against a stronger enemy.
Suara yang seakan menyuruh untuk mencari lawan yang lebih hebat.
타오르는 혼의 부름이!
The outcry of a burning soul!
Raungan jiwa yang membara!
나와 함께 가자.
Let's go together.
Ikutlah denganku.
네게, 아니.
A suitable enemy for you- no.
Lawan yang sepadan dengamu- tidak.
우리에게 걸맞은 적이 기다리고 있다.
A suitable enemy for us is waiting.
Lawan yang sepadan dengan kita telah menanti.
만약 협력하고 싶지 않다면 어쩔 도리가 없지.
If you don't want to work with me, then so be it.
Kalau kau tidak mau bekerja sama denganku, apa boleh buat.
네 마음을 조종해야겠다.
I will have to control your mind.
Aku terpaksa harus mengendalikan jiwamu.
쟌 J. 지킬.
Jean J. Jekyll.
친
Ba
Per
친구
Battle
Perta
친구오
Battle A
Pertar
친구와
Battle Aga
Pertarun
친구와의
Battle Again
Pertarungan
친구와의 ㅈ
Battle Against
Pertarungan An
친구와의 저
Battle Against A
Pertarungan Anta
친구와의 전
Battle Against A F
Pertarungan Antar
친구와의 전ㅌ
Battle Against A Fri
Pertarungan Antar Te
친구와의 전투
Battle Against A Frien
Pertarungan Antar Tema
친구와의 전투!
Battle Against A Friend!
Pertarungan Antar Teman!
친구와의 전투! V
Battle Against A Friend! V
V
친구와의 전투! VS
Battle Against A Friend! VS
VS
친구와의 전투! VS ㅈ
Battle Against A Friend! VS J
VS J
친구와의 전투! VS 쟈
Battle Against A Friend! VS Je
VS Je
친구와의 전투! VS 쟌
Battle Against A Friend! VS Jea
VS Jea
친구와의 전투! VS 쟌
Battle Against A Friend! VS Jean
VS Jean
[[=10.nref2]]
[[=10.nref2_1]]
[[=10.nref2_2]]
[[=13.nref3]]
[[=13.nref3_1]]
[[=13.nref3_2]]
[[=13.nref4]]
[[=13.nref4_1]]
[[=13.nref4_2]]
[[=13.nref5]]
[[=13.nref5_1]]
[[=13.nref5_2]]
드라그온, 저게 뭐야?
Dragwon, what's that?
Dragwon, apa itu?
저 사악한 기운은 틀림없이 가륜의 것이다.
That Evil Aura is definitely Garyun's.
Tidak salah lagi, energi ini adalah milik Garyun
그렇군. 글라디온과 전투할 생각인가.
I see. He must be desiring to have a fight against Gladion.
Begitu. Dia pergi untuk bertarung dengan Gladion.
건방지긴. 블랙 샤크온으로 맞서 줄까.
How impudent of him. Why don't we finish him off with Black Sharkon?
Sombong sekali. Bagaimana kalau kita habisi saja dengan Black Sharkon?
잠깐, 나오키.
Wait, Naoki.
Tunggu, Naoki.
어?
Huh?
Hah?
놈의 사악한 기운은 이전보다 훨씬 강해져 있다.
His Evil Aura is stronger than before.
Energinya jauh lebih kuat dibandingkan yang sebelumnya.
일단은 구경이나 하자꾸나.
Let's observe them for now.
Lebih baik kita perhatikan dulu.
그렇구나. 그것도 재미있겠네.
Alright. That would be interesting.
Baiklah. Itu menarik juga.
뭔 일이야, 켄토.
What's wrong, Kento?
Kento, kau kenapa?
응? 켄토 깨 있네.
Hm, come on!
Hm? Kento, ayo jawab!
아야!
Ouch!
Aduuh!
뭐야, 아오이!
Oh, it's you, Aoi.
Ternyata kamu, Aoi?
뭐긴 뭐야! 이번엔 왜 잠을 못 잤어?
You just realized? What's your reason for waking up late this time?
Baru sadar, ya? Sekarang apa lagi alasanmu sampai bangun kesiangan?
그런 거 아냐. 쟌이야, 쟌.
It's nothing like that. It's about Jean.
Bukan begitu. Ini tentang Jean.
쟌?
Jean?
당분간 연락을 하지 못했어.
I couldn't contact him lately.
Akhir-akhir ini aku tidak bisa menghubunginya.
이런 적은 지금까지 없었는데.
This has never happened before, though.
Padahal, selama ini tidak pernah begini.
무언가 큰일이라도 일어난 걸까.
I wonder if he's in a trouble.
Apa sekarang dia lagi ada masalah ya?
마치 애인 같아.
You two sound like a couple.
Kalian seperti orang pacaran saja.
뭐래니, 얘가!
W-what do you mean?!
K-kamu ini bicara apa?!
지나친 생각!
Don't think too much about it!
Jangan berpikir yang bukan-bukan!
무소식이 희소식!
They say no news is a good news, right?
Orang bilang, tidak ada kabar berarti kabar baik!
쟌!
Jean!
쟌! 뭔 일이야! 연락도 안 돼서 걱정했어! 알긴 알아?
Jean! Where have you been? Why didn't you contact me?!
Jean! Dari mana saja kamu? Kenapa tidak pernah menghubungiku sama sekali?!
켄토. 네게 말할 중요한 게 있어.
Kento, I have something important to talk about.
Kento, ada hal penting yang ingin kubicarakan denganmu.
쟌.
Jean.
매지컬 게이트의 아슬리트 에이리어에 와주길 바래.
I want you to come to Athlete Area in Magical Gate.
Datanglah ke Athlete Area di Magical Gate.
어?
Huh?
Apa?
물론, 글라디온하고 함께.
Together with Gladion, of course.
Tentu saja bersama dengan Gladion.
쟌. 뭔 소리야.
Jean, what are you talking about?
Jean, kamu ini bicara apa?
기다리고 있겠어. 웹다이버, 유우키 켄토.
I'll be waiting, Webdiver, Yuuki Kento.
Ingat, aku menunggumu, Webdiver, Yuuki Kento.
분석 완료.
Analysis complete.
Analisa selesai.
확실히 아슬리트 에이리어에 알 수 없는 반응이 있어뾰꼬.
There is definitely an unknown response in Athlete Area-pyoko.
Di Athlete Area memang ada respon misterius-pyoko.
근데, 에이리어 전체적으로 특수 필드가 뒤덮고 있어뾰꼬.
But the whole area is covered with a special field-pyoko.
Tapi, secara keseluruhan, area itu ditutupi oleh medan khusus-pyoko.
저 안에서 뭐가 일어나고 있는지는 잘 모르겠어뾰꼬.
I don't really know about what's happening in there-pyoko.
Aku juga tidak tahu pasti apa yang terjadi di dalamnya-pyoko.
아슬리트 에이리어는 이전 가륜이 관리했던 에이리어다.
Athlete Area is originally controlled by Garyun.
Athlete Area sebelumnya dikendalikan oleh Garyun.
뭐야, 그거. 그럼 매지컬 게이트에는 나 말고는 들어가지 못하는 거네?
What's the meaning of this? Isn't I the only one who can get into Magical Gate?
Apa maksudnya ini? Bukankah seharusnya tidak ada anak lain yang bisa masuk ke Magical Gate selain aku?
뭔 일이람.
What's up with this, anyway?
Ada apa ini sebenarnya?
어쩔까뾰꼬.
What are you going to do-pyoko?
Jadi bagaimana-pyoko?
당연하잖아. 가야만 해!
That's obvious! I will have to go.
Sudah pasti, kan. Aku akan pergi ke sana.
위험해뾰꼬!
It's dangerous-pyoko!
Bahaya-pyoko!
쟌이 오라고 했어.
Jean told me to do so.
Jean menyuruhku untuk datang ke sana.
tsumazuku hodo nanika ni kakoma re
웹다이브! 글라디온!
Webdive! Gladion!
awatadashiku ikite yuku bokura
kimi no hitomi mitsumete iru dake de
wasurekaketa yuuki ga waku no sa
TOGETHER tooku made
motto ikeru hazu
긴급 발진 대기중.
Emergency dispatch, standby.
Siap untuk diluncurkan.
mune no oku tsumekonda omoi daite
글라디온, 출동.
Gladion, shoot.
쟌, 대체 뭔 일이야.
Jean, what's this all about?
Jean, sebenarnya apa yang terjadi?
WEBDIVER itsu no hi ka
kitto tadoritsuki
hontou no ashita ga bokura ni
hohoende kureru
웹체인지! 글라디온, 파이터 모드!
Webchange! Gladion, Fighter Mode!
TOGETHER out of lonely days
We are going through the way
kinou made no kimi to wa chigau sou sa
WEBDIVER shinjiyou
kitto bokura ni wa
hontou no ashita ga matteru
kanarazu dokoka de
기다렸어, 켄토, 글라디온.
I was waiting for you, Kento and Gladion.
Aku sudah menunggu, Kento, Gladion.
쟌.
Jean.
진짜 쟌 맞아뾰꼬.
It's really Jean-pyoko.
Itu benar-benar Jean-pyoko.
호오? 가륜 녀석과 새 웹다이버군.
Huh. Garyun brought a new Webdiver with him.
Oh, rupanya Garyun punya Webdiver baru.
쟌! 대체 왜 네가 거기에 있어!
Jean! Why the heck are you there?!
Jean! Kenapa kau bisa ada di situ?!
거짓말이야.
No. It's a lie. This is a lie!
Tidak mungkin. Ini tidak mungkin. Ini tidak mungkin!
쟌이 내 적일 리가 없어!
There's no way Jean becomes my enemy!
Tidak mungkin Jean jadi musuhku!
가륜! 쟌에게 뭔 짓을!
Garyun! What did you do to Jean?!
Garyun! Apa yang kau lakukan pada Jean?!
잠깐, 켄토!
Wait, Kento!
Tunggu, Kento!
쟌의 사악한 기운에 대한 반응은 없다.
There is no Evil Aura reaction on Jean.
Tidak terdeteksi adanya hawa jahat pada Jean.
아, 그럼,
So...
Jadi...
쟌은 세뇌된 것이 아니다.
Jean wasn't being manipulated.
Jean tidak dikendalikan olehnya.
자신의 의지로 웹다이버가 된 것이다.
He became Webdiver on his own will.
Dia menjadi Webdiver atas kehendaknya sendiri.
그럴 리가.
No way.
Itu bohong, kan?
거짓말 아니다.
I'm not lying.
Ini kenyataannya, Kento.
쟌은 가륜에게 조종당하고 있어.
Jean is being controlled by Garyun.
Pasti Jean dikendalikan oleh Garyun.
아니라면 그럴 리가...
If he's not, there's no way he would...
Kalau tidak, mana mungkin dia bisa begitu...
아니야, 켄토.
You're wrong, Kento.
Kau salah, Kento.
이건 내가 의도한 거야.
This is just as I wanted.
Ini adalah hal yang aku inginkan.
내가 내 의지로 여기에 왔어.
I came here on my own will.
Aku datang ke sini atas kehendakku sendiri.
내가 가륜의 웹다이버.
I am the Webdiver of Garyun.
Aku adalah Webdiver Garyun.
쟌 J 지킬이다!
Jean Jacques Jekyll!
잘 말했다. 해보자, 글라디온!
Well said. Let's go, Gladion!
Bagus, Jean. Ayo bertarung, Gladion!
가륜. 켄토와 둘이서 이야기하게 해 주지 않을래?
Garyun, may I talk with Kento alone?
Garyun, beri aku waktu untuk bicara berdua dengan Kento.
쟌.
Jean.
알겠다.
You may.
Baiklah.
켄토. 여기가 어딘지 알아?
Kento, do you know what this place is?
Kento, apakah kau tahu tempat apa ini?
여기는 아직 해방되지 않은 에이리어야.
This area hasn't been freed yet,
Biarpun sebenarnya area ini masih belum dibebaskan,
여기는 가륜이 관리하던 에이리어이기도 해.
but Garyun used to manage this place.
tapi dulunya, ini adalah area yang dikendalikan oleh Garyun
너와는 아무래도 여기서 이야기하고 싶었어.
I really wanted to talk with you here.
Aku sangat ingin bicara denganmu di sini.
너와 내가 처음 만난 곳은 바로 여기야.
The place where we met each other for the first time.
Di tempat pertama kali kita bertemu.
너와는 만나기 훨씬 전부터 나는 이 에이리어로 오곤 했어.
I often came to this place long before we met each other.
Jauh sebelum aku berkenalan denganmu, aku sering datang ke area ini.
여기가 딱히 좋았던 건 아니고.
It's not like I loved this place.
Bukannya karena aku suka dengan area ini.
어쨌든, 여기에 왔더니 무언가가 보이는 게 아니겠어.
It's just, I might be able to find something in here.
Tapi, aku mungkin bisa menemukan sesuatu di sini.
아니면 상상했던 것일 수도.
Or so I thought.
Begitulah yang kupikirkan saat itu.
쟌이여.
Dear Jean,
Hai, Jean.
이겨라. 계속 이겨 가라.
Win. You must keep winning.
Menanglah. Kau harus terus menang.
몸을 단련시켜 기술을 닦아 정신을 갈아
Train your body, improve your skill and sharpen your spirit,
Latihlah tubuhmu, asahlah kemampuanmu, tempalah jiwamu,
계속 승리해라.
and keep gaining victories.
dan teruslah dapatkan kemenangan.
그것이 긍지 높은 명문
That is the fate of a person
Itu merupakan takdir bagi orang
지킬 가문에서 태어난 자의 운명이다.
born in the respectful Jeykll family.
yang terlahir dalam keluarga Jeykll yang terhormat.
잘 들었겠지.
Keep that in your mind.
Ingatlah itu.
그 때의 나는 뭘 위해서 펜싱하는 것일까.
At that time, I didn't understand on what purpose
Saat itu, aku tidak mengerti lagi untuk apa sebenarnya
잘 몰랐어.
did I do fencing.
aku terus bermain anggar.
내가 펜싱을 계속하는 진짜 이유는 무엇일까.
I keep wondering the true reason behind me doing fencing.
Aku terus mempertanyakan apa alasanku sebenarnya bermain anggar.
그래서 난 이 에이리어에 왔을 수도 있지.
Maybe that's why I often came to this area.
Mungkin karena itulah aku jadi sering datang ke area ini.
여기라면 무언가를 발견하지 않을까 하고.
Maybe I could find something at a place like this.
Karena di tempat seperti ini, mungkin aku bisa menemukan sesuatu.
그 때, 난 널 처음 만났어.
And at that very moment, I met you.
Dan saat itulah, aku bertemu dengamu.
Brought to you by Subdiver
켄토. 내가 느낀 네 첫 인상을 말해줄까?
Kento, do you know what my first impression was about you?
Kento, apa kau tahu kesan pertama yang kudapat dari dirimu?
첫 인상?
Your first impression?
Kesan pertama?
시끄럽고 허물없는 이상한 녀석.
A weird, noisy guy who's being over-familiar.
Kau anak yang aneh, cerewet, dan sok akrab.
너, 대단해!
You're amazing!
Kau hebat sekali!
그거, 펜싱이라고 하는 거지?
I bet that's called fencing!
Itu yang namanya anggar, ya?
나에게 좀만 보여줘!
Mind teaching me a little bit?
Ayo, ajari aku sedikit!
하겠지만 방해는 하지 마.
I'm sorry, but please don't disturb me.
Maaf, ya, jangan ganggu aku.
아, 이해해. 혼자서 몰래 훈련하는 거지?
Ah, I understand. You want to train quietly alone, right?
Ah, aku mengerti. Jadi kau ingin berlatih sendiri dengan tenang, ya?
이해해.
I truly understand.
Aku mengerti, kok.
나도 검도를 하니까 말이야.
I do kendo too, after all.
Karena aku sendiri suka main kendo.
방해하지 말라니까!
I told you to not disturb me!
Sudah kubilang, jangan ganggu aku!
모를까나... 너같이 대단한 사람을 보고 떨리는 내 기분을.
I think you don't understand my quivering feeling as I see someone as amazing as you are.
Memangnya kau tidak mengerti, ya, perasaanku yang bergetar saat berhadapan dengan seseorang yang hebat sepertimu?
음, 그러니까, 부탁해!
Uh, so, please!
Jadi, aku mohon!
조금만 펜싱 보여줘!
Show me your fencing just a little bit!
Ijinkan aku melihat permainan anggarmu sedikit saja!
그렇게 서는 거구나?
Ah, so that's the stance for it!
Ah, begitu, ya, kuda-kudanya!
멋져!
Awesome!
Hebat!
이 정도면 됐지?
That satisfies you enough, right?
Apa kau sudah puas?
아, 대단해!
Yeah, that was amazing!
Iya, hebat sekali!
그럼,
Bye, then.
Aku pergi.
근데, 그 잠깐만. 발돋움을 강하게 하면 더 위력이 세지지 않을까?
Although, I think your attack will be more powerful if you add more strength when you step on the ground.
Tapi, aku rasa seranganmu bisa jadi lebih dashyat kalau kau menambahkan kekuatan saat memijakkan kakimu.
아, 결코 불평하려는 건 아니고, 음, 그냥 그렇지 않을까 하고 생각해서...
Uh, it's not that I want to complain you, it's just... well... that's just how I felt.
Um, bukannya aku mau merendahkanmu, hanya saja... ya... itulah yang kurasakan saat melihatmu.
그래.
I see.
Begitu, ya.
다만, 실전으로 보여주지 않겠어?
How about teaching it directly, then?
Kalau begitu, ajari aku secara langsung.
승부야!
Let's have a match!
Ayo bertanding!
그 때는 정말로 화났었어.
I was really angry at that time.
Saat itu, aku benar-benar marah padamu.
깨닫게 해 주겠어. 때려눕히겠어. 하고 생각도 했고.
I was almost going to let you know by knocking you down.
Sampai-sampai aku ingin memberimu pelajaran dan membalas kata-katamu itu.
그래도, 난
But you...!
Tapi, kamu...!
알아. 모두 잊지 않았어.
I still remember everything about that. There's no way I could forget it.
Aku masih ingat semuanya. Mana mungkin aku melupakannya.
근데 왜 하필 지금이야!
Why are you suddenly bringing this up now?!
Kenapa tahu-tahu kau membicarakan tentang itu sekarang?!
지금이니까.
Because it is the right time to.
Justru karena sekarang itu.
영문을 모르겠어!
I really don't get it!
Aku tidak mengerti sama sekali!
왜 네가 나와 글라디온의 적이 되어야만 하는데?
Why do you have to be our enemy?
Memangnya kenapa kau harus menjadi musuhku dan Gladion?
그런 필요는 전혀 없어!
You don't have to do that at all!
Bukankah itu sama sekali tidak perlu?!
난 그렇게 생각하지 않아.
I don't think so.
Aku tidak berpikiran seperti itu.
쟌.
Jean.
난 가륜의 기분을 잘 알아.
I understand Garyun's feelings very well.
Aku bisa memahami bagaimana perasaan Garyun.
더욱 강한 상대와 싸우고 싶어 하는 마음.
The desire to fight against a stronger enemy.
Dia terus menginginkan pertarungan dengan lawan yang lebih kuat.
그 기분이.
That kind of feeling....
Perasaan itu...
정말 넌 모르는 거야?
You actually understand that, don't you?
Sebenarnya kau sendiri juga mengerti, kan, Kento?
그만둬, 쟌.
Stop it, Jean.
Hentikan, Jean.
나에게 그 기쁨을 말이야.
The one who taught me that happiness...
Yang mengajari kebahagiaan itu...
내가 몰랐던 세계를 알려준 건.
The one who taught me the world I didn't know is...
Dan juga dunia yang tak kukenal sebelumnya...
켄토. 네 덕분이야.
Kento. It's all thanks to you.
Itu semua karena kamu, Kento.
관둬!
Stop it!
Jangan teruskan!
너에게 난 그 정도의 존재일 뿐인 거야?
Does my existence means nothing much to you?
Aku tahu. Bagimu keberadaanku hanya sebatas itu, kan?
그만두라고 했어!
I told you to stop!
Sudah kubilang, jangan teruskan lagi!
나에게서, 가륜에게서 달아날 거야?
So you want to run away from me, and from Garyun as well?
Kau mau menghindar dariku, dan juga dari Garyun?
달아난다고?
Run away?
Menghindar?
승부다. 유우키 켄토. 나와 싸워 보자!
I'm challenging you, Yuuki Kento. Fight against me!
Aku menantangmu, Yuuki Kento. Bertarunglah denganku!
잘 말했다. 그럼, 내 웹다이버여!
Well said. That's my Webdiver for you!
Bagus. Itu baru namanya Webdiver-ku!
켄토.
Kento.
아, 하겠어. 해 보자.
Ah, I'll do. I'll do it.
Ya, aku terima. Aku terima tantanganmu.
할 때 봐주기 없기다!
I won't go easy on you!
Kalau sudah bertarung, aku tidak akan segan-segan!
승부다! 쟌 J 지킬!
It's a match, Jean J. Jekyll!
Kita mulai, Jean J. Jekyll!
응.
Okay.
Baiklah.
웹다이브! 글라디온!
Webdive! Gladion!
젠장... 어째서 이렇게...
Damn... how did it come to this...
Sial... kenapa harus begini...
켄토. 네가 결정한 것이다.
Kento, you've made a decision.
Kento, ini adalah keputusanmu.
taiyou wa shiranai
점점 재밌어지네.
It finally begins.
Ini dia. Sudah waktunya.
mune wo kogasu itami kitto
가륜. 새 웹다이버의 힘을 잘 보여줘 보라고.
Garyun. Show me the power of your new Webdiver.
Garyun, perlihatkan kehebatan Webdiver-mu yang baru.
itsuka daichi wa sabaku ni umore
kono kawaki kitta omoi mo
kimi ni deaeta kara
iyashite kureta kara zutto
motomeru kimochi SINKU suru toki
mou boku wa hitorikiri janai
좋아, 그럼 진심으로 싸워 볼까나.
That was good. I'll be serious from now.
Bagus. Aku akan serius sekarang.
kimi ga iru kara hashiri daseru
맘대로 하셔.
Do as you want.
Lakukan sesukamu.
해보자!
Let's do it!
Ayo maju!
mezameteku shinji au chikara
켄토. 괜찮아?
Kento, are you okay?
Kento, kau tidak apa-apa, kan?
아직이다. 이 정도일 뿐인가, 글라디온!
We aren't done yet. Is that all you got, Gladion?!
Masih belum. Apa cuma itu yang kau bisa, Gladion?!
저 놈, 아직...!
That guy is still...!
Dia belum menyerah...!
여기까지다, 가륜.
I'll call it a fight, Garyun.
Cukup sampai di sini, Garyun.
뭐?!
What?!
Apa?!
이 이상 하면 단지 서로 부수는 싸움이 될 뿐이야.
If we do more, we'll just destroy each other.
Kalau melakukan lebih dari ini, hanya saling menghancurkan saja.
의미가 없어.
There's no point of doing so.
Tidak ada artinya.
그럴 리가. 난 아직!
No way! I'm not done yet!
Yang benar saja! Aku masih bisa!
네가 원하는 전투는 이 정도일 뿐이었니?
Is the fight you desire for this low?
Apa pertandingan yang kau inginkan cuma sebatas itu saja?
무슨 의미냐.
What do you mean?
Apa maksudmu?
난 싫어.
I won't do it.
Aku tidak mau.
모처럼의 승부를, 우리의 전투를 이런 모양으로 끝내긴 싫어!
I don't want the match that I've wanted for so long to end like this. I wouldn't!
Aku tidak ingin pertarungan kita harus berakhir dengan cara seperti ini saja! Aku tidak suka itu!
쟌.
Jean.
뭔 소리냐. 이제 와서 비실거리는 소리 마라!
What are you talking about? I won't let you back away now!
Bicara apa kau? Tidak akan kubiarkan kau mundur sekarang!
가륜. 난 켄토와 싸우고 싶다는 생각은 했지.
Garyun. I did want to fight against Kento.
Garyun, aku memang ingin bertarung dengan Kento.
그래도 난 켄토의 적이 되고 싶다고는 생각한 적 없어.
But I never thought about wanting to be Kento's enemy.
Tapi aku sama sekali tidak ingin bermusuhan dengan Kento.
다치게 할 생각 없어.
I never thought to hurt him, too.
Aku juga tidak ingin melukainya.
가륜. 글라디온하고 싸우고 싶다고 했지? 그것도 계속 싸우고 싶지 않니?
Garyun, do you want to fight Gladion, or do you want to hurt him instead?!
Garyun, apa kau ingin bertarung dengan Gladion, atau kau hanya ingin menyakitinya?!
내가, 내가 원하는 것은 진검승부다!
I... What I want is an earnest battle!
Aku... yang kuinginkan adalah pertarungan yang jantan!
나는.
I am...
Aku...
대단해, 펜싱이란.
Fencing is truly awesome.
Anggar itu luar biasa, ya?
이렇게 대단하리라고는 생각도 못 했어.
Never thought it could be this fun before.
Tidak aku duga kalau bisa seseru ini.
또 하자.
Let's do it again sometime, yeah?
Kapan-kapan, kita bertanding lagi, ya?
또?
Yeah.
Iya.
기술을 발전시켜야지. 네 승부에도 도움이 되고.
We've improved our techniques. By putting more strength, we will fight better than before.
Kita sudah asah kemampuan. Dengan menambah kekuatan, kita bisa bertarung dengan lebih baik lagi.
재미있어, 펜싱.
You want that, right? Fencing sure is fun, huh.
Mau, kan? Anggar itu menyenangkan, ya, kan?
맞아.
That's true.
Kau benar.
그런데, 네 이름은 뭐야?
By the way, what's your name?
Ngomong-ngomong, namamu siapa, ya?
그 때 나는 처음 펜싱이 재미있다는 생각 했어.
I thought fencing was fun for the very first time in my life at that time.
Saat itu, untuk pertama kalinya dalam hidupku, aku merasa anggar itu menyenangkan.
그렇게 내 생각도 바뀌었고.
And then, something inside me had changed!
Lalu, sesuatu dalam diriku sudah berubah.
재미있다고?
Fun?
Menyenangkan?
이기는 게 모든 건 아니야.
Winning is not everything.
Kemenangan bukanlah segalanya.
그보다도 중요한 것들을 얻기 위해서라면
Sometimes, there's a battle to improve each other's skill.
Kadang-kadang ada juga pertarungan untuk saling meningkatkan diri masing-masing
서로 만나 진검승부도 하고.
And by doing so, we'll get something more important than winning.
dan mendapatkan sesuatu yang lebih penting dari kemenangan.
켄토가 가르쳐 준 것은 그런 전투.
It was Kento who taught me such battles.
Itulah pertarungan yang diajarkan Kento kepadaku.
무슨 소릴!
That's stupid!
Itu bodoh!
너와 나는 같아.
You are the same as I was.
Kau sama denganku dulu.
이기는 것밖에 모르지. 작은 세계에 갇혔지.
A man fixated solely on victory; no wonder you're trapped in such a small world.
Hanya terpaku pada kemenangan. Karena itulah, kau terkurung dalam dunia yang sempit.
그 때의 나야!
You're me of that time!
Kau adalah diriku saat itu!
시끄럽다! 입 다물어라!
Hold your tongue! Shut up!
Jangan banyak bicara! Diam!
가륜. 싸우기 위해 적이 될 필요는 없어.
Garyun, there's no need to be an enemy in order to have a match.
Garyun, untuk bisa bertarung, tidak harus jadi musuh.
너라면 충분히 알 텐데!
I expected you to know that!
Seharusnya kau mengerti tentang hal itu!
닥쳐라!
Shut up!
Diam!
어떻게도 이해가 가지 않으면, 세뇌를 하든 뭘 하든 해서 내 말을 들어줬으면 좋겠어!
If you still don't want to understand, just brainwash me or anything- do as you like!
Kalau kau masih tetap tidak mau mengerti juga, lakukan sesukamu; cuci saja otakku!
쟌, 너...
Jean, you...
Jean, kamu...
나는!
I am..!
Aku...!
사악한 기운이 사라졌다!
His Evil Aura has disappeared!
Energi jahatnya lenyap!
잘 됐어뾰꼬! 가륜이 완전히 쟈기의 구속에서 해방되었어뾰꼬!
Good-pyoko! Garyun is completely freed from the restraint of Evil Aura-pyoko!
Bagus-pyoko! Garyun berhasil melepaskan dirinya dari energi jahat-pyoko!
글라디온. 우리 전투는 일단 중단이다.
Gladion. We'll have to postpone our match.
Gladion. Terpaksa kita tunda dulu pertarungan kita.
가륜.
Garyun.
그러나, 난 너와의 승부를 낸 것도, 동료가 된 것도 아니다.
But that doesn't mean I'm giving up on settling our match, and that also doesn't mean I am one of your friends now.
Tapi, bukan berarti aku menyerah untuk membuat perhitungan denganmu, dan juga bukan berarti aku menjadi temanmu.
일단은 데리트로스를 박살내고 보겠다!
First, we'll finish Deletloss off, and then, we will settle everything else!
Pertama, kita habisi Deletloss. Setelah itu, baru kita selesaikan semuanya!
좋다.
I accept.
Baiklah.
개소리 집어치워라!
Enough of this prattle!
Sudah cukup!
가라! 블랙 재규어온! 웹솔저!
Go! Black Sharkon! Websoldier!
Maju! Black Sharkon! Websoldier!
블랙 샤크온!
Black Sharkon!
귀찮은 녀석들이군.
What a troublesome bunch.
Merepotkan juga mereka.
어때. 다시 그걸 해 볼까!
So, would you like to do that again?
Bagaimana kalau kita lakukan yang itu?
좋아. 네 팔에 녹이 슬지만 않았다면야.
Agreed. As long as your skill haven't rusted yet.
Baiklah. Itu kalau kemampuanmu masih belum berkarat.
걱정하지 마라!
Don't worry about that!
Tak perlu kau khawatirkan itu!
가자!
Let's do it!
Ayo kita lakukan!
좋다!
Yep!
Ayo!
웹체인지! 가륜, 어택 모드!
Webchange! Garyun, Attack Mode!
글라디온, 샤이닝 모드!
Gladion, Shining Mode!
글라디온과 가륜이!
Gladion and Garyun...
합체했다!
They combined!
Mereka bergabung!
샤이닝 볼트!
Shining Bolt!
대단해! 저렇게 많은 적을 일격에!
That's cool! They can defeat an enemy that many just by a single blow!
Hebat! Lawan sebanyak itu dimusnahkan dalam satu serangan!
해냈어, 켄토!
We did it, Kento!
Berhasil, Kento!
기분 좋다.
It feels good here.
Udaranya segar, ya.
켄토, 나는...
Kento, I'm...
Kento, aku...
켄토.
Kento.
이제부터 나도 싸울게. 가륜하고 함께.
From now on, I'll fight together with Garyun too.
Mulai sekarang, aku akan ikut berjuang bersama dengan Garyun.
젠장. 가륜 놈, 잘도!
Damn you, Garyun! How dare he!
Garyun kurang ajar! Beraninya dia!
걱정 마라. 내 상처가 거의 다 나았다.
Don't worry. My wound is healed.
Jangan khawatir. Lukaku sudah pulih.
드라그온!
Dragwon!
비록 글라디온과 가륜이 하나가 되긴 했지만, 우리에게 적은 없다.
Gladion and Garyun might have joined together, but they still aren't worthy to be our enemy.
Biar Gladion dan Garyun bergabung sekalipun, tetaplah bukan lawan kita.
나는 무적이다. 우리야말로 최강이다!
I am invincible. We are the strongest!
Aku tidak terkalahkan. Kita adalah yang terkuat!
그래, 드라그온.
That's right, Dragwon.
Itu benar sekali, Dragwon.
Screenplay
Uetake Sumio
Storyboarding
Takata Atsushi
Staging
Katou Shigeru
Voice Actor
Yuuki Kento
Gladion
Arisugawa Aoi
Asaba Naoki
Kobayashi Yumiko
Sugita Tomokazu
Kikuchi Shiho
Takeuchi Junko
Karon
Kaida Yuki
Voice Actor
Jean J. Jekyll
Nakai Masataka
jikuu koete michi e no tobira wo
Voice Actor
Garyun
Konishi Katsuyuki
Dragwon
Kawada Shinji
Old Knight
Nojima Akio
akete yukeba mirai e no SAIN
aratana kuni hikari ga matataku
bokura ga ima mezashiteru sekai sa
TOGETHER kakemegure
motto doko made mo
kinou made no kimi to wa chigau sou sa
WEBDIVER shinjiyou
kitto bokura ni wa
hontou no ashita ga matteru
Ending Theme
SYNC ~because you exists~
Insert Song
Lyrics
Composer
Suzuki Kisaburo
Arranger
Kyouda Seiichi
Singer
Lyrics
Takatori Hideaki
Composer
Hirama Akihiko
Arranger
Singer
Columbia Japan
Production Cooperation
Animation Production
AEON (We've)
Subtitle
Subdiver
ファン字幕
サブダイバー
kanarazu dokoka de
Thank you for watching!
Production
Preview for Next Episode
부활한 웹나이트들.
The resurrected Webknights.
Webknights yang telah bangkit kembali.
쟈기에서 해방된 가륜.
Garyun, who are freed from Evil Aura.
Garyun yang telah bebas dari energi jahat.
그리고, 새로운 웹다이버, 쟌!
And a new Webdiver, Jean!
Dan adanya Webdiver baru, Jean!
이 동료들과 함께라면 데리트로스는 무섭지 않아!
With these friends gathered, Deletloss is totally not terrifying!
Dengan terkumpulnya teman sebanyak ini, Deletloss sama sekali tidak menakutkan!
기다려라, 카이토! 우리가 힘을 합쳐 반드시 매지컬 게이트를 구해 보이겠어!
Just wait for us, Kaito! We'll combine our powers and save Magical Gate!
Tunggulah kami, Kaito! Kami akan menggabungkan kekuatan kami dan menyelamatkan Magical Gate!
전뇌모험기 웹다이버의 다음 이야기!
Next episode of Dennou Boukenki Webdiver!
Di episode Dennou Boukenki Webdiver selanjutnya!
Stay tuned
for the
next story!
Thanks for watching! - Subdiver
See you at http://subdiver.soreepeong.com/ !